# **PETR KOVAR**

## PERSONAL DETAILS

Email: pmkovar@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/pmkovar
Technical blog: blogs.gnome.org/pmkovar/
GitHub: github.com/pmkovar/

CV source code: github.com/pmkovar/pmkovar.github.io

## **SUMMARY**

My expertise lies in technical communication, and project and program management, with a focus on delivering clear, effective documentation. I'm experienced in community management and open source software development, where I engage and connect both the community and corporate contributors.

Additionally, I'm skilled in technical translation, working within open source translation communities to make software and documentation accessible worldwide.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# 8/2018–9/2023 **Documentation Program Manager, Red Hat**

Brno, Czechia

- Played a key role in reestablishing and transforming a writing group for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization into an agile team.
- Developed new workflows and mentored team members to ensure their success in an agile environment.
- Oversaw release management, task planning, and tracking.
- Integrated 15+ Kubernetes and OpenShift-based tools and the Red Hat Developer Program projects into a unified, Jira-centered documentation project, bringing together 25+ writers under a cohesive framework.
- Project Management · Program Management · Agile & Waterfall Methodologies · Task Assignment · Jira · Cloud-Native Applications · DevOps · Kubernetes · OpenShift

#### 3/2015-8/2018

## Senior Technical Writer, Red Hat

Brno, Czechia

- Developed a content strategy for single-sourcing Red Hat Enterprise Linux desktop documentation, ensuring seamless delivery across both community and enterprise products.
- Contributed to transforming CloudForms content into topic-based documentation, utilizing a new docs-ascode toolchain built on Asciidoc.
- $\bullet \ \ Content \ Strategy \cdot Continuous \ Integration \ and \ Continuous \ Delivery \ (CI/CD) \cdot Topic-based \ Authoring \cdot Markdown \cdot Sphinx \cdot AsciiDoc$

# 4/2011-3/2015

# Technical Writer II

Brno, Czechia

- Developed content for key areas of Linux platform and cloud products, including package management, identity and access management, and desktop on Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
- Served as the documentation lead for the desktop area, establishing single-source workflows and collaborating with the GNOME and Fedora documentation and translation communities.
- ullet Linux  $\cdot$  DocBook  $\cdot$  XML  $\cdot$  Technical Writing  $\cdot$  Bash  $\cdot$  Git  $\cdot$  Single Sourcing  $\cdot$  Content Management

# **PROJECTS**

# 8/2017-3/2019

# **Documentation Project Team Lead, OpenStack**

- Elected Project Team Lead of the OpenStack Documentation Project by the OpenStack community.
- Responsible for documentation release management, community engagement, writers mentorship.
- Represented the documentation project by running documentation sessions at OpenStack summits and Project Team Gatherings.
- As a writer, maintained Red Hat-specific content provided by the OpenStack Documentation Project.
- · Collaborated on building and running the OpenStack documentation site.
- Co-maintained the RDO project site.
- $\ \, \textbf{Release Management} \cdot \textbf{Coaching \& Mentoring} \cdot \textbf{Community Management} \cdot \textbf{Community Engagement} \cdot \textbf{Community Outreach} \\$

#### 8/2017–Present

## Lead, GNOME Documentation Project

- Lead a team of community writers to create comprehensive user, sysadmin, and developer documentation for
  official GNOME releases.
- · Oversaw maintenance, issue resolution, and release management of documentation packages.
- Contributed to the information architecture for both desktop and online documentation.
- Organized and facilitated documentation meetups, workshops, and hackfests to engage and support the broader GNOME community.

#### 4/2010-Present

#### Member of the GNOME Translation Project Coordination Team, GNOME

- Collaborate with the Coordination Team to manage the l10n.gnome.org platform, overseeing issue resolution and user management for 50+ GNOME translation teams.
- Approved code freeze exceptions as part of the GNOME release process.
- Organized community meetups for the GNOME translation community at annual GUADEC conferences.

#### 2007-3/2018

# Czech Translation Team Coordinator, GNOME Translation Project

- Coordinated a team of community translators. Responsible for onboarding and training, ticket reporting and escalation, and delivering translations for official GNOME releases as well as third-party projects hosted by GNOME, such as GIMP.
- Organized meetups for Czech translators across various open-source projects under the L10n.cz platform, fostering collaboration and knowledge sharing within the community.

# **EDUCATION**

# 2015–2018 Masaryk University

Brno, Czechia

• Bachelor of Arts — BA, Information and Library Studies

## **CERTIFICATES**

• Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), issued 9/2012

## **LANGUAGES**

- English full professional proficiency
- Czech native proficiency